Guide to the William Nelson Parker Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Additional Material, 1950s-1980s; Accession 1995-M-104; 2 linear feet (2 boxes)
  - The modern state: structure and policy (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - National growth in the 19th century: France (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - National economics in the 19th century: Germany (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - German industrial organization (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - National cases: Russia (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Mercantilism (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Rationalism, Utilitarianism, Liberalism (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - England as a national economy (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Religion, ideology, and capitalism (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - "World Economy" industrial growth: diffussion from Europe (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Organizations in world economy: capital, labor, state (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Science and technology in the 19th century in England, France, and Germany (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - National economies: England, France, Germany (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - The international economy: real factors (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - The international economy: finance (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Economic fluctuations, 1830-1940 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - The inter-war period (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Population and food, 19th and 20th century Europe (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Co-determination (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Latin America (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - India (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Japan (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Africa (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Course outlines, reading lists, etc. (Box 2, Folder 52-53)
  - Midterms and final exams (Box 2, Folder 54-55)
  - British colonial policy (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - American Revolution (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - History of law: capitalism in the early republic (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - South to 1790 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - South and slavery (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - North, 1750-1860 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - South and Midwest, 1865-1940 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - West: agriculture and minerals (Box 2, Folder 63-64)
  - Railroads, 1840-1940 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - U.S.: agriculture (Box 2, Folder 66-67)
  - Rural society/agriculture (Box 2, Folder 68-70)
  - Agricultural organization (Box 2, Folder 71-72)
  - Technology (Box 2, Folder 73-74)
  - Population and labor force (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - Industrial organization: scale and regulation (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - 19th century capital, money, and credit (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - Politics and economics, 1800-1930 (Box 2, Folder 78)
  - Children's school book on American economic history (Box 2, Folder 79)
  - American economic history (Box 2, Folder 80)
- Additional Material, Accession 2001-M-033
  Conditions Governing Access
  Correspondence in boxes 15-18 is unprocessed and in a physical state that would prohibit use. Researchers wishing to request access should email mssa.assist@yale.edu requesting specific box numbers in order to initiate the review process, which may take several weeks.
  - School files, 1920s-1930s (Box 1–2)
  - Diaries, 1930s-1990s (Box 3–7)
  - Topical files, 1990s (Box 8–9)
  - Yale University School of Management, 1980s (Box 10)
  - Correspondence, 1920s-1990s (Box 11–14)
  - Correspondence, Circa 1920s-1990s (Box 15–18)
    The material is unprocessed and is in a physical state that would prohibit use. Researchers wishing to request access should email mssa.assist@yale.edu requesting specific box numbers in order to initiate the review process, which may take several weeks.